Audio Recording Needs

This appendix chapter is a plea for money. Feel free to return to the Appendix Index if you either can not or do not want to assist.

Please do not offer to help with these expenses in the immediate. I want to set to a Gofundme for it, but I want this field guide to be further along when I do, and then I will want donations to go through the gofundme so there is more transparency in what has already been received. Before I hit the field to make recordings, I really should spend more time researching and writing species descriptions.

I have a financial need for the purchase of audio recording equipment. It is not cheap, but it will greatly benefit the quality of this project.

First I will describe my goals, and then the hardware I need to make audio recordings myself for the benefit of this project.

Of course I will accept audios recorded by others, if they meet the quality standards I need to be very picky about.

Audio Goals

A long-term goal of this project is to have quality audio recordings, loudness normalized to the EBU R128 Loudness standard, for as many bird, frog, and insect calls as possible.

For both quality and legal reasons, it really is my preference if these recordings are original to this project with the recordings made in either Contra Costa or Alameda Counties.

Both birds and frogs, and quite likely insects, have dialects. In fact these dialects often are a part of how speciation takes place.

When the dialects in different areas have diverged enough, they create a barrier to gene flow that results in the divergent populations heading down different evolutionary paths.

It is my strong desire for as many audio recordings as possible to have photo vouchers accompanying the recording to help validate the species that was recorded, along with geolocation data. This information should be vouchered in the iNaturalst with audio recordings also submitted to the Cornell Lab of Ornithology Macaulay Library.

A lot of taxonomy work in birds is taking place, and there certainly will be Cryptic Species Complexes discovered where variations in the song are one way to distinguish species within the complex.

With birds, an identifiable photo voucher of the actual bird being recorded can also verify whether the song is coming from a male or female of the species, there is often sexual dimorphism in the singing and it would be great to have songs from both sexes available in the species profiles.

Types of Audio Recordings

There are two basic types of audio recordings I want to have as part of this project:

Single Specimen Recordings
This is the recording of the sound made by a specific specimen to the exclusion of noise around it. These recordings are best done with a directional microphone aimed at the specimen to be recorded.
Chorus Recording
This is the recording of the sound made by group, often separated from each other enough that directional microphones do not work for this kind of recording.

Audio Mastering

For submissions to Macaulay Library, it probably is best for NO modifications of the PCM data to take place, for risk of damaging the waveform. The researchers that use the audio recordings should have the original data.

For use within this field guide, some mastering will take place, specifically the perceived loudness normalization so that all audios within the field guide have the same perceived loudness.

For audios recorded with a Parabolic Microphone, they are great for a directional recording at a distance but they distort the recording. The physics of how they work, higher frequencies are amplified more than lower frequencies.

Using a high-pass filter to remove frequencies below what it wanted first, it may be possible to use a digital filter to compensate for this frequency-based amplification distortion by digitally amplifying the lower frequencies above the high pass filter, similar to how the RIAA Equalization curve works. I still have to look into it.

Each audio should also have a clear voice with a short description of the species and other data (such as sex) prepended to the audio, to help avoid confusion.

For space reasons, after normalization the audios will be lossy encoded using the Ogg Opus container and codec at 64kbps. Opus is a mature IETF standard that has been well-supported by everyone except Apple for years. The problem with using AAC, unless you use HEv1 profile there is no guarantee an ePub player that supports audio will be able to properly decode it, often resulting in very subpar playback. With the HEv1 profile, you need a much higher bitrate to get the same quality you can get with Opus at 64kbps. File size then becomes a very real issue.

Hopefully in the not too distant future, Apple will get over itself and support Ogg Opus. They already support the Opus codec itself since iOS 11, but they still refuse to support the Ogg container needed for it to work with their ePub readers.

Audio mastering will be done with a combination of Audacity, SoX, FFmpeg (for EBU R128 normalization), and Opus Tools.

Those are high quality free software projects and do not have any cost involved. Well, other than my time.

Hardware Description

When nature is your recording studio, there are several different hardware components that work in conjunction with each other:

Digital Recording Device
Microphone & Battery Pack
Pistol Grip with Foam Wind Screen

Digital Recording Device

For quality recordings, which is the goal, the quality of the microphone is far more important than the quality of the digital recording device. The microphone takes the sound waves and converts them into an analog electrical current signal. It does not matter how good the ADC in the recording device is if that current signal is crap.

That being said, if the digital recording device is too low quality, the electrical signal it converts to bits will suffer greatly. Smart phones do not cut it, they degrade a quality input signal.

The recording device must be able to handle at least 48kHz/24 bit PCM data smoothly. 24 bits per sample gives more flexibility when setting the recording level, you can be a little conservative without suffering audible quantization noise when amplifying the recording later. If the recording level is too high, the recording clips and is useless, but if you record too low with 16 bits per sample, amplifying during mastering can result in audible quantization noise.

XLR for the microphone input is beneficial but not absolutely mandatory if the device has a quality 3.5mm microphone input jack. A cheap 3.5mm connector can create noise in the signal before the conversion to digital takes place.

The recording device must also have sufficient use time before that battery needs to be recharged, and should have replaceable batteries if they run low while out in the field.

For me, the size of the unit is also a consideration. I like to hike, I already carry camera equipment etc. and do not want a recording unit that is too large.

The recording device that meets all my needs is the Roland R-07. It lacks XLR support but I do not see that being a huge issue.

As a compact unit, this also would make a good backup unit to carry with me in the future if I ever do upgrade to a more expensive unit.

The Roland R-07 costs about $200.

Another option is the Tascam DR-100MkIII. It has the advantage of an XLR input and rates a little better in recording quality according to Macaulay Library tests, but the battery does not give as many hours of record time and it costs $100 more.

With respect to the better recording quality, that was measured by spectral analysis tests rather than human listening tests. Whether the difference is audible or not to human ears, that was not tested. Differences in spectral analysis differences are not always audible in double blind listening tests.

The battery life is a potential issue if used for Chorus Recording. I honestly think I would rather put the $100 difference into the microphone.

Microphone & Battery Pack

When the Digital Recording Device has an XLR input it actually can be used to power the microphone as well. With only a 3.5mm jack, the microphone needs its own power source. Even with an XLR input, I think I would prefer the microphone to have its own power source anyway.

I have no plans to use a parabolic microphone. They do have farther directional range than a shotgun microphone, but they require more skill in targeting them and are more difficult to pack for hiking due to the parabola dish.

For recording Chorus Recording, I actually plan to build my own, explained in a minute.

The microphone I need to start recording audios for this project is a shotgun microphone. There are two options I am considering:

Rode NTG2

This shotgun microphone is the cheaper option at around $270 but Macaulay Library reports that it is noisier at high frequencies. With most birds and amphibians that probably is not an issue, but it is an issue with bats and insects, both of which will be covered in this guide.

It can be powered with AA size batteries.

Sennheiser ME 67/K6P

The Sennheiser ME 67 seems to be a favorite among bird recordists, but it requires the use of a battery pack.

B&H Photo sells a kit that has both for about $460. That kit is probably the way to go, the K6P battery pack is a good battery pack.

This is roughly a $200 price difference over the Rode NTG2.

For that price difference, I would get both better recordings of high audio frequencies and better directional recordings of everything, reducing the noises that I do not want to record when doing a Single Specimen Recording.

Pistol Grip with Foam Wind Screen

Regardless of which of the two shotgun microphones I end up getting—for recording wildlife audio—a pistol grip with a wind shield is an absolute must.

The directional mic will not be mounted to a video camera, and even the slightest breeze creates considerable noise in the recording if there is not a foam wind screen.

A proper pistol grip will have dampners to reduce vibration transmitted to the microphone from handling the grip.

The quality of the foam wind screen apparently can make a huge difference in recording quality if the wind is stronger than a gentle breeze.

There are some kits for both a pistol grip and a wind screen but I really need to do more research to make sure the kits contain quality for both.

The ‘Rycote Lyre Mount with Pistol Grip Handle’ looks like it probably is the grip to use, and it costs about $85.00. There is a kit that comes with that grip and what appears to be a decent wind screen for about $155.

Cost Analysis

If I end up going with the less expensive Rode NTG2, the Digital Recording Device + microphone + grip/wind screen comes to about $625. With the more expensive Sennheiser ME 67/K6P option, it comes to $815.

With a very conservative estimate of 25 bird song recordings during the first twelve months, not including my field time or time in mastering the recordings for the field guide, that comes to a cost of $25 per audio recording. With the more expensive microphone, that cost would be $33 per recording. Basically an additional $8 per recording for the better quality microphone.

During the initial year of use, I will probably make more than 25 usable recordings for the field guide. In subsequent years the number of recordings will likely drop as the easy to locate and record species will already have been recorded. This is why I used the first year only for the cost analysis. Hopefully I will get as many as 35 bird song recordings during the first year (remember male songs often differ than female) but 25 is my conservative goal. There are also insects and frogs to record, and maybe bats if I can manage it.

Chorus Recording

For recording a chorus, whether it be frog or bird, I think I want to use a “Poor Man’s” binaural microphone.

One thing I have noticed with Sierran Chorus Frogs, when the entire pond is not in chorus, they often call in identifiable triplets.

Frog A will call from one part of the pond, followed by Frog B from a different part of the pond, and then Frog C from yet another.

I noticed a similar thing with Red-winged Blackbirds when at Cattail Pond at Helen Putnam Regional Park near Petaluma.

One group of two or three Red-winged blackbirds would call from one part of the pond, followed by a second elsewhere, followed by a third elsewhere, followed by silence. Then it would repeat.

A binaural microphone setup is basically a faux human head with realistic ears and a microphone in each ear. The intent is that by listening to the recording with headphones, you can get a three dimensional effect.

The expensive part of a binaural microphone is the fake head, they cost over $400 and I suspect are overkill for this project. I personally want to try using a seven inch diameter styrofoam ball. That is the approximate diameter of a human head. An eight inch styrofoam ball is about $10 or so at art supply stores and is close enough to seven inches.

The BE-P1 binaural microphone is $175. That includes a battery box needed for the amplifier.

With respect to the behavior I have observed in chorus frogs and blackbirds, my suspicion is that this done for the purpose of confusing predators that zoom in on their chorus. By calling in coordination from different parts of the pond, it may confuse some predators.

Do the frogs and blackbirds and frogs behave that way only when I am near because I am a perceived predator, thus an observer affecting the observed? Or do they also behave that way if I am some distance away?

I may never know the answer to that question, but I would like to try and record the behavior whether or not I can detrmine if it is in response to a potential threat stimuli.

If it works and the listener is wearing headphones, the stereo effect should be similar to if their head was where the binaural microphone was placed, and in theory they should be able to distinguish the relative direction different calls were coming from.

Ideally this would do this with the cooperation of a park ranger when the park is closed to the public to reduce the odds of device theft, but for recording things like Coyotes, it probably could be set up near a tent where I am camping without having an impact on the Coyote vocal behavior.

This binaural recording experiment is in the future, I will not be trying this for some time.

Conceptual Terms

This appendix contains terms of a conceptual nature that are intrinsically linked categorically.

Species Population Residence Classification

This section defines terms related to the classification of a species based upon the residence nature of the population within Contra Costa County.

Native Species

A naturally occurring species. A Native Species is a species that reproduces within Contra Costa County for which the reproducing population either dispersed into Contra Costa College by natural means from a naturally occurring population elsewhere or evolved within Contra Costa County as part of a chronospecies population that was present in the geographical region before Contra Costa County became a designated entity.

Examples of a Native Species include the California Red-legged Frog (Rana draytonii), the Blue Oak (Quercus douglasii), and the quite likely now extinct Sooty Crayfish (Pacifastacus nigrescens).

A quite possibly unacheivable goal of this field guide is to eventually include every Native Species that can be observed without the aid magnification, including those that are now extinct, that were present within the county when John Marsh first settled here.

Natural Migrant Species

A regular naturally occurring visitor species. A Natural Migrant Species is a species that does not regularly breed in Contra Costa Costa County but for that can be found resising here during part of the year as a regular migration pattern that is part of the natural history for the species.

Examples of a Natural Migrant Species include the Hooded Merganser (Lophodytes cucullatus) and the Golden-crowned Sparrow (Zonotrichia atricapilla).

A quite possibly unacheivable goal of this field guide is to eventually include every Natural Migrant Species that can be observed without the aid magnification, including those that are now extinct, that were present within the county when John Marsh first settled here. It may be realistic to achieve this goal with birds within a few years, but I do not know if it is realistic to achieve this goal with insects.

Vagrant Species

Occassional visitor by natural means. A Vagrant Species is a species which wander into Contra Costa County most likely from a wild population, but for which visiting Contra Costa County is accidental rather than part of their natural history.

An example of a Vagrant Species that has visited Contra Costa County recently is the Eastern Kingbird (Tyrannus tyrannus) for which a sighting was confirmed in 2017 at Heather Farm.

Vagrant species will generally not be covered in this field guide unless they have visited more than once. For example, Humphrey the Humpback Whale (Megaptera novaeangliae) visited Contra Costa County in 1985 but it would be ridiculous to include Humpback Whales in this guide.

Whether or not to include a Vagrant Species will generally be left up to the discression of the curator for the taxon group the vagrant falls within. As chief editor I would say yes to the Eastern Kingbird if the Avian Curator wanted to include it, but no to the Humpback Whale if the Mammal Curator wanted to include it. Unless of course it starts to happen with more frequency and with more than one wayward whale.

Domesticated Species

A Domesticated Species is a species that has undergone many generations of selective breeding by humans either for agricultural purposes, decorative purposes, or for the pet trade.

Generally speaking, the selective breeding process has altered the genetic diversity of the species such that it has obvious phenotype differences from the wild stock it was domesticated from.

In many cases, the process of domestication with animals alters an animal such that it becomes dependant upon humans and can not survive as a wild animal outside of urban areas or has a radically different natural history than its non-domesticated counterparts.

Examples of Domesticated Species frequently encountered interacting with our wild ecology in Contra Costa County include the Domestic Pigeon (Columba livia domestica), the Domestic Cat (Felis catus), and Cattle (Bos taurus).

The inclusion of non-feral Domesticated Species within this field guide will generally be left up to the discression of the curator for the taxon group the Domesticated Species falls within.

Released Curiosity

A Released Curiosity is a pet that either escapes or is released, or an exotic animal brought in by accident, for which there is no indication of a functioning population.

An example of a released curiosity in Contra Costa County would be the Chinese Fire-bellied Newt (Cynops orientalis) I found within Tilden Regional Park in 2010 (photo voucher at http://www.naherp.com/viewrecord.php?r_id=41483). Various pet turtles are also often intentionally released, several different species can be spotted at the artificial pond at Los Medanos College, such as the Spiny Softshell (Apalone spinifera) and the Western Painted Turtle (Chrysemys picta bellii).

The inclusion of Released Curiosities within this field guide will generally be discouraged unless it is a somewhat common occurrence.

Introduced Species

An Introduced Species is a species with a sustaining population that did not come to Contra Costa County by natural means. Usually a sustaining population means it is reproducing. In some cases, however, the population may recruit new members by continual releases of pets and might not be reproducing in sustainable quantities at all.

An example of an introduced species that does sustainably reproduce is the Rio Grande Wild Turkey (Meleagris gallopavo intermedia). An example of an introduced species that largely depends upon continual pet releases is the Red-Eared Slider (Trachemys scripta elegans).

Given a very long period of time, it is possible for an Introduced Species to become a Native Species, co-evolving balance with the ecosystem. This appears to be the case with the Dingo in Australia. Quite often a lot of existing Native Species are driven to extinction in the process.

A quite possibly acheivable goal of this field guide is to eventually include every extant Introduced Species that can be observed without the aid magnification.

Inclusion of Introduced Species that are no longer extant will generally be left up to the discression of the curator for the taxon group the Domesticated Species falls within.

Feral Species

A Feral Species is used for a population that has gone wild from relatively recent domesticated ancestors. With the exception of feral equines (not present in this county), as a result of domestication feral populations generally have a different natural history and often a different phenotype than their wild ancestral stock.

Examples of feral species in Contra Costa County include the Feral Pig (Sus scrofa domesticus) and the Feral Pigeon (Columba livia domestica).

All feral species are also introduced species.

Invasive Species

An Invasive Species is an Introduced Species that quickly establishes new populations at a high ecological cost to native species, sometimes causing their extinction. In some cases, it is easy to make the case that an Introduced Species is an Invasive Species. In other cases, it may be somewhat of a judgement call.

Clear cases of Invasive Species within Contra Costa County include the American Bullfrog (Lithobates catesbeianus), the Argentine Ant (Linepithema humile), and the Signal Crayfish (Pacifastacus leniusculus).

In some cases for Invasive Species not yet present, at the discretion of the discression of the curator for the taxon group a potentially Invasive Species falls within, it may be included in this field guide.

An example of such a species would be the Red Imported Fire Ant (Solenopsis invicta). To the best of my knowledge, no populations are known within Contra Costa County. Including that species in this field guide may help identify a population while it can still be destroyed, preventing an infestation.

Habitat Types

This section different biome habitat types often found within Contra Costa County.

Chaparral Habitat

Chaparral is a Mediterranean Climate biome visually dominated by shrubs adapted to survive drought conditions and frequent wildfires. The shrubs that grow in them are often referred to as ‘drought resistant’ but in many respects, I think a better term would be ‘drought dependant’ because if the periodic droughts we experience did not happen they would likely get choked out by other types of plants.

The shrubs that grow in chaparral generally have very woody stems that branch out low to the ground and tough leaves that do not dry out easily.

Open-scrub Chaparral refers to a denity of shrubs that is low enough a person can easily enter the area and walk between the shrubs without needing to destroy them. This type of chaparral is often accompanied by low-growth wildflowers, basking lizards, rabbits, and coyotes. Silver Lupine (Lupinus albifrons) is an example of a shrub that is frequently associated with Open-scrub Chaparral.

Closed-scrub Chaparral refers to a density of shrubs that is high enough it is difficult for people (or other large mammals) to penetrate without destroying some of the shrubs. This type of chapparal is often utilized by small rodents and ground-dwelling birds. Mount Diablo Manzanita (Arctostaphylos auriculata) is an example of a shrub that is frequently associated with Closed-scrub Chaparral.

If the Berkeley Kangaroo Rat (Dipodomys heermanni berkeleyensis) is still extant, it almost certainly is dwelling within chararral habitat.

Desert Chaparral

While not applicable to Contra Costa County, Desert Chaparral is a form of chaparral habitat found in rain shadows rather than in a mediterranean climate. Desert chaparral typically covers less than half of the available land as less water is available.

Riparian Habitat

Riparian is the lush growth habitat that often grows directlty adjacent to a permanent stream, river, or lake, utilizing the water provided by the adjacent stream, river, or lake.

Riparian habitat is unfortunately often damaged by city development and the alteration of the watershed, people like to build communities where there is water and where water does flow through urban areas, often there are houses and concrete preventing the growth of riparian vegetation.

Works Cited

Academic Journal References

Alvarez et. al. 2013
Alvarez, Jeff A., David G. Cook, Julie L. Yee, Michael G. van Hattem, Darren R. Fong, and Robert N. Fisher. 2013. Comparative Microhabitat Characteristics at Oviposition Sites of the California Red-legged Frog Rana draytonii. Herpetological Conservation and Biology, 8(3), 2013, pp. 539–551.
Barry and Fellers 2013
Barry, Sean J. and Gary M. Fellers. 2013. History and Status of the California Red-legged Frog (Rana draytonii) in the Sierra Nevada, California, USA. Herpetological Conservation and Biology, 8(2), 2013, pp. 456-502.
Conlon et. al. 2007
Conlon, J. Michael, Ahmed al-Dhaheri, Eissa al-Mutawa, Rokaya al-Kharrge, Eman Ahmed, Jolanta Kolodziejek, Norbert Nowotny, Per F. Nielsen, and Carlos Davidson. 2007. Peptide defenses of the Cascades frog Rana cascadae: implications for the evolutionary history of frogs of the Amerana species group. Peptides, 28(6), 2007, pp. 1268–1274.
Jennings and Hayes 1985
Jennings, Mark R. and Marc P. Hayes. 1985. Pre-1900 Overharvest of California Red-legged Frogs (Rana aurora draytonii): The Inducement For Bullfrog (Rana catesbeiana) Introduction. Herpetologica, 41(1), 1985, pp. 94–103.
Starkey et. al. 2003
Starkey, David E., H. Bradley Shaffer, Russell L. Burke, Michael R. J. Forstner, John B. Iverson, Fredric J. Janzen, Anders G. J. Rhodin, and Gordin R. Ultsch. 2003. Molecular Systematics, Phylogeography, and the Effects of Pleistocene Glaciation in the Painted Turtle (Chrysemys picta) Complex. Evolution, 57(1), 2003, pp. 119–128.

Glossary of Terms

Jump to letter: A C E G I M N P Q S T U V

Allele
A specific variation of a gene that occurs at the same place on the chromosome as other variations of the same gene. New alleles are created by random mutations in the copying of existing alleles, and may rapidly spread by organism reproduction through the species via natural selection if the mutation provides a benefit to the species.
Chordate
Animals within the phylum Chordata. All vertebrates are members of the Chordata phylum.
Chronospecies
A species defined in the context of a time frame. Many chronospecies have evolved into populations with a distinctively identifiably different phenotype and are therefore classified as a different species in the newer time frame.
Conspecific
When two or more populations are the same biological species, they are said to be conspecific.
Cryptic Species Complex
A species complex for which it is very difficult or even impossible to classify some specimens to the specific species within the complex based purely on the visually expressed phenotype.
Extant
Continues to have a surviving population.
Extirpated
A formerly reproducing population that no longer exists is an extirpated population. Locally (or globally) extinct.
Genetic Diversity
The variation of alleles available within a population.
Genotype
The genetic makeup of a particular individual organism, the specific alleles that specific organism inherited from its ancestors.
Introgression
The transfer of alleles that evolved in one grouping of organisms into another grouping of organisms through hybridization events between the two groupings.
Monophyletic
When a grouping of organisms is descended from a most recent common ancestor to the exclusion of all organisms not within the grouping, the grouping is called a monophyletic grouping. Contrast with paraphyletic.
Monotypic
A taxonomical grouping containing only one species. A taxonomic grouping higher than the species level (such as a genus) that only contains a single species is referred to as a monotypic grouping, whether or not multiple subspecies are described. A species that does not contain any subspecies is less commonly but also referred to as a monotypic species.
Mutualism
Describes the ecology where two or more biological species interact with each other for the mutual benefit of all species involved.
Natural History
In the context of a species, the study of the natural behaviours of a species in all of its life stages and how the species interacts with the environment around it and the ecogical niche in ecology of the environment around it.
Neotonic
In biology, neotonic generally refers to an animal in the larval stage of a species that does not go through metamorphis to the next life stage but continues in the larval stage.
Paraphyletic
When a grouping of organisms for which known organisms outside the grouping also descended from the most recent common ancestor of the grouping, the grouping is called a paraphyletic group. In the taxonomy ‘Tree of Life’ (e.g. Class, Order, Family, Genus, Species, etc.), paraphyletic groups are avoided as much as possible. Contrast with monophyletic.
Phenotype
The observable expression of a genotype, influenced by natural selection or (in captivity) selective breeding. Please note that it is not always easy to determine if an observable characteristic is the result of the genotype or another factor, such as diet or climate.
Quantization
In Mathematics, when values from a large (often but not always infinite) set are mapped to a smaller subset of values, it is called quantization. For example, there are an infinite number of length value between 0 and 1 meter, but if we measure something to the nearest millimeter, we are are mapping that infinite set to a smaller finite set that contains 1000 possible values.
Quantization Error
Quantization Error is the difference between an actual value in a set and the quantized value it is assigned. Basically the rounding error.
Quantization Noise
Usually used in terms of audio and images, when an analog signal is quantized for digital storage, quantization noise is the difference between the analog signal that can be reproduced from that digital signal and the original band-limited analog signal before it was quantized. In audio, audible quantization noise has the characteristics of tape hiss. In audio recorded at 16 bits per sample at safe listening levels, quantization noise is only audible when the recording volume was too low. Increasing the bits per sample during recording gives more leeway with the recording volume, as the resulting quantization error is smaller. Professional equipment usually uses 32 bits per sample even though most professioal sound engineers are skilled enough to get by with just 16.
Shutterbug
A camera enthusiast who really enjoys pursuing high quality photography. Shutterbugs are very important to field guides and citizen science.
Speciation
The evolutionary process in which a population within a species differentiates itself from other populations within the species to become a distinct separate species from those other populations, on a different evolutionary path.
Species Complex
Two or more species that are so closely related they are difficult to distinguish from each other and may still have frequently occurring gene flow (introgression) happening.
Tetrapod
The monophyletic group including all vertebrates that possess four limbs, and all their descendants (such as snakes and legless lizards).
Ungulate
Hoofed mammals, such as deer and cattle and horses and pigs.
Vertebrate
Chordates that possess a backbone.